CURRICULUM VITAE

Johannes Jurgens du Toit

07/01/2013

Introduction

Hello, my name is Jurgens du Toit (I like to spell it jrgns), and if you're for a Head of Development or Systems Architect, I'm it.

I love the internet and the possibilities it provides, and I love building things for the net. I'm a natural problem solver, with a knack of building solutions in elegant and creative ways for problems that will normally stump my peers. I try to pick up new skills every year, so I have some experience with a lot of technologies out there.

I believe that with enough thought and some effort, most business problems can be solved, or at least made less of an issue, using technology. The skill I most value in this context is that of being able to bring order to chaos. If you leave me in a room filled with any type of chaos for long enough, it will be neat and ordered when you come back. A subset of this is the ability recognizing and exploiting patterns using technology to solve problems efficiently.

The second most important skill I have is the ability to quickly find and assimilate information on a subject. Nobody knows everything, but, using available resource, including the internet, I can add what I need to know to my current knowledge base in a relatively short time. This enables me to do understand the full stack scope of an issue – from the implementation to the business issues at hand. I believe that seeing the bigger picture improves my ability to solve detailed issues much faster.

I'm easy going, with the ability to work alone or in groups. I tend to gravitate to leadership roles, although I'm perfectly happy to follow the lead of someone more capable or experienced than me. Yes, it all sounds very middle of the road, but that's who I am: An introverted, creative technician that loves interacting with people.

Now for the details:

Name and Contact Details

Surname: du Toit

Name: Johannes Jurgens (Jurgens)

ID number: 811003 5029 080

Marital Status: Married to an awesome wife

Date of Birth: 3 October 1981
Nationality: South African
Cell Number: 083-511-7932

E-mail Address: jurgens.dutoit@gmail.com

Twitter @jrgns

Website http://jrgns.net

GitHub https://github.com/jrgns

Drivers License: Code 08

Education and Qualifications

School - Hoërskool Vorentoe High School, Johannesburg

Subject	Symbol
Afrikaans (HG)	A
English (HG)	В
Mathematics (HG)	Α
Science (HG)	Α
Computer Science (HG)	В
Technica: Electronics (HG)	С
Additional Mathematics (HG)	В

University:

Summary

- Enrolled at the Rand Afrikaans University (RAU) for B.Sc(IT) in 2000
- Achieved Distinctions in four First Year subjects, namely Computer Science, Mathematics, Mathematical Statistics and Electro technique
- Graduated at the end of 2002
- B.Sc (Informatics) Honnours with an average of 68%
- M.Sc (Computer Science) dissertation entitled "Resolving E-assessment security issues using agents" in 2007. This included the development of a Firefox plugin written in JavaScript

Academic History

1st Year (2000)	1st Semester	2nd Semester
Computer Science 1	93	81
Mathematics 1	77	75
Mathematical Statistics 1	76	75
Business Management 1A	63	
Electro technique 1B		82

2nd Year (2001)	1st Semester	2nd Semester
Informatics 2	72	60
Computer Science 2	70	58
Mathematics – Calculus 2	69	50
Mathematics – Algebra 2	64	56

3rd Year (2002)	1st Semester	2nd Semester
Informatics 3	60	59
Computer Science 3	63	50

4th Year (Honnours) (2003)	1st Semester	2nd Semester
Systems Programming	70	
Functional Programming	70	
IT Project Management	56	
Graphical Programming		71
Parallel Programming		65
WWW Programming		64
Project (Using PHP, HTML, SQL and CVS)		79
Ethical and Legal aspects of IT		69

Skills Matrix

Type of Experience	Experience in months	Date Last Used	Skill
PHP	132	Current	5
HTML	132	Current	4
CSS	88	Current	3
JavaScript	88	Current	4
JQuery	36	Current	3
Node.js	12	2011	3
MySQL	132	Current	4
Unit Testing	24	Current	4
Linux System Administration	132	Current	4
Bazaar	42	Current	4
Git	36	Current	4
System Design and Architecture	60	Current	4
Client and Server side WebServices	72	Current	4
Integration with Third Parties	72	Current	4
PHP Frameworks such as Symfony, Backend-PHP, Zend and Lithium	60	Current	4
Various other languages such as Ruby, Perl and SML/NJ	12	2007	2

^{1 =} Appropriate Training, 2 = Limited practical experience, 3 = Solid practical experience, 4 = Well versed extensive experience, 5 = Expert extensive experience.

Employment History

March 2012 to Current: Prefix (www.prefix.co.za)

Lead Developer: Integrations

Responsibilities:

- Drive and develop integration of product (everlytic.com) with third party applications and networks, ie. Salesforce.com, Facebook and Twitter
- Design and development of 2nd generation API
- · Manage integrations team
- General guidance and education to whole development team
- Interface with and assist Support and Sales departments regarding integration
- Increase stability of the product through continuous testing and integrations strategies.

March 2010 to December 2011: Branded Internet (www.brandedinternet.co.za) January 2012 to Febuary 2012: Data Pathway (www.datapathway.co.za) *Head of Development / CTO*

Reason for leaving: BI was closed down and some of the staff and the client base moved to Data Pathway. Did not agree with the new company culture and ethics. Responsibilities:

Recruitment and training of developers and system engineers

- Upgrading and replacing legacy systems
- Oversee and manage maintenance and building of system
- API development
- Interface with other departments
- General leadership and strategising for the technical side of the company
- Contribute to management of the company
- Explore available technologies, assess their potential impact on the company, and implement where necessary.

October 2008 to March 2010: Branded Internet (www.brandedinternet.co.za) Developer

Reason for leaving: Promoted

Responsibilities:

- PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript development for internal and external systems.
- Setup and maintenance of source repositories
- Database maintenance
- · Interface with System Administrators
- Product Development

October 2005 to September 2008:

Contractor:

Reason for leaving: Wanted a stable income

- Web design and development (Personal / JadelT cc):
 - jrgns.net
 - iadeit.co.za
 - whatsupinmelville.co.za
- Web development (Interpix)
 - rapidinfo.co.za
 - o fatebu.co.za
 - o referco.co.za
 - VOIP Billing system
 - Various HTML/Javascript projects
- Development (OpenVoice)
 - Development and maintenance of Collaborator HTML and Stylesheet editor.
 - Development and maintenance of Collaborator Questionaire JavaScript
 - backend.
- Datamining and analysis for STATKON (Statistical Analysis department of UJ)

October 2005 to 2006: Cherry Creek Software(www.cherrycreeksoft.co.za) Developer/Contractor

Reason for leaving: Wanted to pursue contract work Responsibilities:

- Upgrading current HTML and Javascript technologies.
- Development of client solutions using Visual Basic 6, ASP and ASP.net
- Use of inhouse software to create solutions for clients.

January 2003 to July 2005: Modiredi Services (www.modiredi.co.za) Contractor

Responsibilities:

- Implementation and customization of Open Source software such as OWL.
- Contract web development (Base system of www.predictabid.com)
- In house software development using PHP.

System and Database adminstration for Web/E-mail servers.

June 2000 to November 2003: STATKON (Statistical Consultants for RAU) Student Assistant

Responsibilities:

- Administration: Basic Admin, Deliveries and Client Contact.
- Statistical Analysis: Basic Analysis such as Frequencies, Chi-Square, Cross tabs and Factor Analysis.
- Basic IT support for the department. This includes hardware upgrades, custom software development for the department as well as for customers.

January 2004 to November 2004: UJ IT / Computer Science Department Student Assistant

Responsibilities:

- Administration: Student marks a,nd practical lists.
- Marking: Assignments and tests.

Leadership Experience

2012: Lead Developer at Prefix.

2010 – 2012: Head of Development at Branded Internet. CTO from November 2011.

2000 – 2007: Various leadership and organizer positions for various teams, short term outreaches and initiatives for the DR Church in Melville

Achievements

- Top 10% in Stackoverflow's PHP tag, top 20% for MySQL, and top 12% overall: http://careers.stackoverflow.com/cv/publish/48937
- Was invited to the RAU's First Year Top Achievers function with an average above 75%
- Matriculated as Dux of my class
- Built an open source PHP framework. See it on my github page.

Hobbies and Interest

- Reading
- Tropical fish tanks
- Music, both classical and modern. I play a some guitar.
- The Outdoors and Hiking
- Startups

References

Lance Terner – Branded Internet (CEO)

Cell Number: +27 83 667 9999

Email: lance@brandedinternet.co.za

Rolf Nel – Interpix

Cell Number: +27 82 863 7910 Email: rolf@interpix.co.za

Rev. Ben Klut – Reverend, DR Church Johannesburg

Cell number: 082-898-7938 E-mail: benelise@mweb.co.za